export const MINA_ADVANCE_QUESTION = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is the role of the Ouroboros Samasika protocol in Mina?",
    options: [
      "To validate transactions",
      "To create new blocks",
      "To maintain a constant blockchain size",
      "To secure the network"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "How does Mina achieve its constant blockchain size?",
    options: [
      "By using zk-SNARKs",
      "By limiting the number of transactions",
      "By using a centralized database",
      "By frequently pruning old blocks"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 0,
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "What is the purpose of a snark worker in the Mina protocol?",
    options: [
      "To produce blocks",
      "To generate zk-SNARK proofs",
      "To validate transactions",
      "To store the blockchain"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What is the significance of zk-SNARKs in Mina?",
    options: [
      "They allow for private transactions",
      "They enable scalability by compressing blockchain data",
      "They provide a consensus mechanism",
      "They are used for encrypting data"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "What is the role of a block producer in the Mina blockchain?",
    options: [
      "To validate transactions",
      "To create new blocks",
      "To secure the network",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "How does Mina ensure the security of its network?",
    options: [
      "Through a large number of nodes",
      "By using zk-SNARKs",
      "By implementing the Ouroboros Samasika protocol",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "What is the main advantage of using zk-SNARKs in Mina?",
    options: [
      "High transaction throughput",
      "Low transaction fees",
      "Scalability and privacy",
      "Fast block creation"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "What is the function of the Mina token (MINA)?",
    options: [
      "To pay for transaction fees",
      "To participate in staking and consensus",
      "To govern the protocol",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "How does Mina handle transaction validation?",
    options: [
      "Through a centralized authority",
      "By using zk-SNARK proofs",
      "By relying on miners",
      "By using a proof-of-work mechanism"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "What is the primary goal of the Mina blockchain?",
    options: [
      "To achieve high transaction speeds",
      "To maintain a lightweight and scalable blockchain",
      "To provide a centralized platform",
      "To offer high transaction fees"
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1,
  },
];